Western democratic institutions are different.
Democratic institutions in the US, UK, and most European countries have taken different forms.
All forms, though, aim to effectively represent the people's will in the governance of their government.
Chinese cyber citizens ("netizens") has always described the Internet as a place for people to vent their anger.
But are they aware that our government officials actually pay attention to all their comments?
In contrast, the "yellow vest" movement in France
up till now, has already been ongoing for 16 weeks.
You will find what people complain most is that the government doesn't listen to the public.
The government turns a blind eye to them.
There is a word called "responsive".
It is used to describe whether the government responds to people's needs,
regardless of the way it exercises its power.
The US election system is well designed.
For example, a president is elected every four years.
But how many promises, to what extent has the former one realized?
During the election campaigns,
Trump promised to force Mexico pay for the to-be-built Mexico border wall.
But in reality, the Americans are the ones paying for it now.
And he even declared a national emergency to build the wall, avoiding legal proceedings.
So as Luojun mentioned, that kind of democracy is designed to be flowery.
In that democracy, you can express your views freely.
However, the government can choose to listen or not.
Can you imagine such things happening in China?
It is impossible.
If people are criticizing the government strongly,
our government will definitely deal with it in a very short time.
Right.
If you're too slow to respond even by a day or two, you will be badly scolded.
The key reason why our government responds quickly is that
they really cares about its people's opinions.
Just now, you took the example of the US, France and maybe other countries.
Usually, we may simply just say this is a good system.
But in actuality, we forget to look closely at the system.
There are barriers to the implementation and may cause further problems.
We should reflect on the system carefully.
In this episode, Prof.Zhang will answer the question of how to practice democracy in China?
Actually, this is not a question only for China, but for the whole world.
We want democracy, and they also want that.
How did China carry out democracy?
In February, I read an article on a website.
It is written by an editor of Wirtschaftswoche, a German weekly business news magazine.
He wrote in the article that
only 40% of Germany trusted their government,
but in China, the percentage of it reached 86%.
After knowing such a gap, he had this question,
is Western representative democracy dying?
When competing with China's model of governance,
how can western countries carry out their promise to a prosperous life for the people?
That's from an influential German economic media.
Chinese people should maintain their ability to think independently.
We shouldn't regard democracy as the perfect answer and just copy it.
How to develop a democracy is a worldwide problem.
China Now with Zhang Weiwei
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade
鹊桥小队翻译组
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie
公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Hello everyone. Welcome to China Now.
We are here to learn about China, understand China,
and position China!
Standing next to me is our keynote speaker,
Professor Zhang Weiwei, Director of China Institute of Fudan University.
There are many people in the audience today, including our pre-production panel.
We will listen to the speech by Prof. Zhang and brainstorm together.
In the last episode, we discussed democracy.
And about democracy, Prof.Zhang still has something to say.
I will give you the floor.
Thank you.
We surf the Internet frequently.
We may know some netizens never compare China with democracies that "are worse off".
For example, if you say Iraq and Afghanistan are democracies,
but their democracy has been one worse than the other.
People may ask, why do you compare China with these democracies that "are worse off"?
If you say another democracy India, is not developing well,
they may ask, why do you compare China with India?
Why don't you compare China with the US?
And then if you point out that
in the past 40 years, democracy in the US failed to increase the income of the majority of Americans and has instead led to populism.
They may ask, why do you always compare China with democracies that "are worse off"?
Why don't you compare it with Northern European countries?
Actually, if I get the opportunity, I also would like to talk about Northern European countries.
They are comparable.
Those who say not to compare China with countries that "are worse off" actually have a bad mindset.
They can't tolerate when people say China is doing good or that China is developing really fast.
Generally, these people still have a longing for the western system.
They think, as long as China's system and ways of doing things are different from the west's,
then China must be the one in the wrong way.
To put it straight, they are accustomed to kneeling to the west and can no longer stand up with confidence.
The concept of comparing "who's worse" originated from the west, not China.
I did some research and found it was a saying from the British Prime Minister Winston Churchill:
"It has been said that democracy is the worst form of Government except for all those other forms that have been tried from time to time."
So democracy is the least bad of them all.
Well, of course, what he said was in the Western context.
He supported to continue the colonization in India.
He didn't know India would be a democracy.
He thought it was impossible.
So I think this is the earliest comparison of "who's worse".
If someone asks you not to make such comparisons next time,
you should tell him that this originated from Churchill.
I think that this famous saying of Churchill actually misled many people,
causing some countries to stagnate.
In fact, the Western democratic system has a lot of problems,
but they still don't think it a problem,
since the other systems are not as good as a democracy.
I always said that Western countries have been fooling others in recent years.
They asked other countries to copy their system, believing it is the best in the world,
which is depicted in the book "The End of History".
They have fooled others and themselves into thinking that their system is the best,
but more and more problems have emerged within their systems.
I would even say it becomes a bad democracy.
This is the first topic of today.
A good democracy is good, but bad democracy can only be bad.
I have traveled to many countries,
and I have seen the adversity, difficulties, dilemmas, and disasters
brought about by Western democracy to other countries.
I can empathize.
So my conclusion is very simple.
If we want to talk about democracy,
we must make a distinction between good democracy and bad democracy.
Otherwise, there will be big problems.
As early as in 2006, I pubilshed an article, "The Allure of Chinese Model,"
on the international edition of The New York Times
I criticized the Western countries for straining to export their democracy model,
and even waging wars to achieve it.
I wrote the West imposed its democracy model,
bringing a lot of problems to developing countries.
"The American model is largely ideology driven,
with a focus on mass democratization.
With little regard to local conditions,
it treats sub-Saharan Africa or other less developed countries as mature societies
in which Western institutions will automatically take root.
It imposed democratization before a culture of political tolerance and the rule of law was established.
The end result has often been discouraging or even devastating."
I quoted the research of two American scholars, Edward Mansfield and Jack Snyder.
They wrote a monograph, the title of which is very interesting,
"Electing to Fight: Why Emerging Democracies Go to War".
They gave a large number of examples.
After the so-called democratized and free elections in the 1990s,
those countries immediately entered a state of war.
Armenia's war against Azerbaijan,
Ecuador against Peru,
Ethiopia against Eritrea,
and massacres broke in Burundi and Rwanda,
killing more than one million people.
It is the same as how the Arab Spring turned into the Arab Winter.
In 2003, George W. Bush launched the Iraq War
and a plan to push Arab democracy reform.
He said the roots of terrorism lie in the non-democracy of Arab countries.
But in 2006, he put this plan aside. Why?
Because in that year, following the rule of One Person One Vote,
Palestine elected Hamas, a terrorist organization in the eyes of Americans.
But around 2011, when the Middle East was in chaos,
the United States began to promote the so-called second wave of democratization in the Middle East, the Arab Spring.
The whole West was cheering for it.
The great western democracy finally arrived at the Arab.
Later, we saw the result,
the Arab Spring turned into the Arab Winter.
Millions of refugees have entered Europe or have been preparing to go to Europe,
which has become the most difficult political problem in Europe, messing up European politics.
Indeed the West imposing western democracy on other regions represents a belief,
the one I call "democracy fundamentalism",
which has brought too many problems and disasters to the world.
I went to a German think tank for an academic exchange last year.
I spent some time on the population of refugees from the Middle East
and the negative impacts on Europe and Germany.
They estimated that,
at least 3 million refugees from the Middle East were waiting to enter Europe in Turkey.
Some German scholars described them as the hostages of the Turkish government.
Turkey often asked for money from Germany with the refugees.
Well, this is one side of the story from Germany.
In addition, at least 3 million refugees are waiting throughout North Africa.
In Libya alone, there were no less than 1 million.
They are also ready to flock to Europe at any time.
To be frank, the German Chancellor, Angela Merkel's initial planned to take the lead in accepting refugees
because Germany needed cheap labor after all.
So she welcomed refugees from the Middle East in the name of human rights and humanity.
She was indeed a bit naive.
She assumed that other EU members would follow her steps.
Unexpectedly, other EU members forgot the universal value and
and sent the refugees to German's gate.
It was such a good deal if German would accept them all.
Eventually, German politics suddenly fell into a dilemma.
Merkel also gradually lost some of her prestige.
And she is preparing to withdraw from the political arena.
In fact, the Europeans reap what they sowed.
Why did you support the Arab Spring so strongly?
If they had seen the end, would they do the same?
On the topic of democracy, many great thinkers in the West also had many thoughts.
I would share some of their thoughts with you.
I think their thoughts can help us understand and build democracy better.
When it comes to democracy,
we usually date back to ancient Greece, the birthplace of Western democracy.
It was a primitive democracy.
In ancient Greece, there were many so-called city-states in different sizes.
Their population was roughly the same as those of the villages or towns in China today.
In those so-called city-states,
citizens, excluding women and slaves,
who were the majority of the population,
could decide whether to fight with other city-states in the ecclesia,
and how to punish criminals.
You may have known a great philosopher named Socrates in Athens.
He was charged with corrupting the youth’s ideology,
and was sentenced to death by the democracy of “one person, one vote”.
Therefore, his student, Plato, another great philosopher in ancient Greece,
was bitter and indignant about his death.
He believed that democracy was actually mob politics,
because men were different from each other in intelligence, morality, and ability.
However, in the democratic institution of Athens, the differences were ignored.
In such an institution, it was assumed that
all male citizens should have the same political rights,
so the result will inevitably lead to mob politics.
He told a story.
If you were ill,
would you go to see a well-trained, qualified and experienced doctor
or ask someone without medical knowledge for treatment on a city square?
He said, of course, you would choose a professional doctor.
And for a country,
the governor's responsibility and difficulty would be a hundred times more than a doctor's.
Whom would you rely on?
There is no doubt that we should find an experienced and qualified person with governing capacity.
I think that Plato's idea is similar to China’s.
Governing a country needs talents.
Talents must be tempered and qualified.
The ideal democracy should be very sophisticated and rich in culture and content,
but the West over-simplified democracy,
ignoring all important things--national condition, culture, tradition, education, and the rule of law.
They think a country that has a multi-party system and the rule of one person one vote, is a democracy.
As a result, so many bad democracies were born in the world.
Far too many countries have made this mistake
and suffered long-term turmoil, wars and economic recessions.
Their people are living in misery.
Today, Western countries themselves also realize the crisis caused by democracy fundamentalism.
So history has repeatedly proven that
a good democracy is for the benefit of people,
while a bad democracy can be nothing but a disaster for the people.
As you may know,
Adolf Hitler, elected in a multi-party system with a rule of one person one vote,
is an example of bad democracies.
In 1933, Germans were strongly dissatisfied with the economy and society,
especially the unemployment of young people,
Hitler’s Nazi Party exploited the situation and easily won 37.4% of the votes by means of populism,
becoming the largest party in the German parliament.
Germany is renowned for nurturing rational philosophers,
but the Germans elected Hitler by the rule of one person one vote in the multi-party system.
He brought a catastrophe to Germany
and even almost destroyed the entire Western civilization.
I think, if Plato could have been alive until 1933,
he might have said, I’ve already foreseen this.
We can also talk about Aristotle, another ancient Greek thinker.
Aristotle had such an insight,
the success of democracy requires two elements:
the first is to have a large group of the middle class;
the second is the rule of law.
Without a relatively large group of the middle class,
Aristotle believed, democracy could hardly succeed,
because in a polarized society, the poor would be jealous of the rich,
As a result, society would be constantly unstable.
He believed that the middle-class would act as a stabilizer in society
because they are satisfied.
They are not as well off as the upper class but better than the lower class.
He believed that the rule of law was also very important,
because when maintaining a democracy, especially one with various disputes,
we can't resolve problems without the rule of law.
If they are not well settled, they may get more serious and even destroy a country.
It can be seen in international politics that
once there is a dispute on the counting of the ballots,
generally, the supreme court decides the final result.
However, in many countries, people don't accept the arbitration of the supreme court.
In that case, the rule of law doesn’t work and eventually leads to chaos.
Let's think about this.
After adopting the western democratic system,
many countries have been thrown into crisis and turmoil.
Indeed, it has something to do with these two factors.
One is the lack of a middle class.
Or it's too small.
the other is the absence of the tradition of the rule of law.
In the past, there was a view that
western countries were all mature democracies, especially the US.
It seemed that they would never experience such crises.
You may remember that Donald Trump and Hillary Clinton had a campaign debate.
The host of the TV show, Wallace (if I remember right) asked Trump
if he lost, would he accept the result of this voting?
Trump, facing the camera and hundreds of millions of viewers,
didn't answer this question directly.
He said, it depended on the situation and he would like to keep it as a secret.
In another debate, he said he would accept a completely fair and justice voting result.
The words meant more than he said.
He reserved the right to question and investigate if the results were questionable.
In other words, in the past, no matter what happens,
The Supreme Court's decision must be accepted whether you agree or not.
Now even the United States begins to question it.
Therefore, the mainstream US media was in an uproar.
They thought it was unimaginable that
US presidential candidates prepared to challenge the rule of law
and US politics became more and more similar to that of the third world.
The recent situation is also going this way.
US media often reported that Trump was facing various charges,
including secret communication with Russia, tax evasion and affairs.
so that he might even be impeached.
But according to Trump's lawyer, Rudy Giuliani, a senior Republican politician as well,
if Trump was impeached,
the United States might sink into chaos,
and some Trump supporters would revolt.
Many reports already said that if Trump got impeached, his fans would riot.
So many Americans lament that
the democracy that the United States once took pride in
is declining to the level of third world countries.
Trump has declared several times that the United States is a developing country,
so that he wants to make the United States great again and
lift it out of the group of developing countries.
In addition, when we talk about democracy,
we certainly cannot skip another very important French enlightenment thinker, Rousseau.
He put forward the idea of popular sovereignty relatively early in the West.
This idea inspired generations of Europeans,
especially the Frenchmen with lofty ideals
who could even sacrifice themselves in pursuit of democracy.
In his work " The Social Contract", he put forward a very insightful idea,
that Chinese scholars are not likely to cite it.
He proposes that if you live in a very small country with only 10,000 citizens,
the influence of the vote in your hand can be measured as 1/10,000.
But if the population rises to 100,000,
the influence of your vote will be reduced to 1/100,000, only one-tenth of the former one.
In this way, if the population is 1 million,
your influence will be even smaller, only one-hundredth of the first one.
So his conclusion is simple.
The larger the population is, the smaller the influence of the vote is,
and the farther the politics is from you.
Therefore, he thinks that democracy with elections is only suitable for small countries,
especially those without a large wealth gap or intense social conflicts.
Otherwise, democracy will be difficult to implement.
I think it makes sense.
The larger a country is, the smaller influence people can feel from their votes.
This is the serious issue that a country like China with a population of 1.4 billion
should consider when developing democracy.
I would also like to talk about another famous scholar of Western liberalism called Friedrich Hayek.
He also has many doubts about democracy.
He believes that democracy should be strictly defined as a decision-making process,
a kind of procedural democracy, rather than the ultimate value.
Democracy itself is not the final goal.
No matter what’s your remark on Hayek's liberalism,
it’s indeed a very controversial idea.
He said, "We never intend to create a fetish of democracy.
It may well be that our generation consider and discuss too much of democracy
but too little of the values it aims to serve."
I think it is quite insightful.
He is strongly opposed to the abuse of democracy in most countries,
because even decisions made by the majority are not necessarily legitimate.
For example, if the majority reach a consensus on dividing up the property of the minority,
this is not legitimate.
The concept of fetish of democracy defined by him is also interesting.
Itis a bit like the democracy fundamentalism in our words.
Almost all of those who strive to promote Western democracy or American democracy to the world,
are believers in the fetish of democracy and democracy fundamentalism.
They advocate implementing democracy just for democracy
and think it a must to adopt the Western form.
We have seen the result -- so many countries have been torn apart.
And the fetish actually has caused the West to decline along the way.
With the outbreak of the financial crisis in 2009
and the Arab Spring turning into the Arab Winter,
the attraction of Western democracy is rapidly fading out in the world.
But we should still note that
although Western democracy has suffered serious setbacks,
the dividend of Western democracy hasn’t been totally depleted yet.
Some people are still being fooled, which is actually very stupid.
Considering things above,
I think we shouldn't simply conclude that democracy is good.
We may say cars are good because they run faster than horse-drawn carriages.
But we also need to consider the condition of the road.
If we are on a muddy path, cars can’t go smoothly.
Moreover, we have other vehicles that move faster than cars,
such as high-speed rails, magnetic levitation trains, airplanes and so on.
And we can invent new things.
So instead of regarding democracy as a good system,
we should say good democracy is a good system.
Then some people may ask,
would your expressions complicate discussions on this issue?
For example, when we define socialism as a good thing,
should we refer it in particular as good socialism instead?
Actually, someone asked me this question.
I don't think the issue is that complicated. Why?
The point is that the concept of democracy was "registered" by the west first.
Now when you talk about democracy,
in most countries people will immediately think of Western democracy
with a multi-party system with the rule of "one person one vote".
The west defines democracy as western democracy and this narrative dominates.
As a result, we often misunderstand democracy.
As for socialism, such a kind of misunderstanding is not likely to happen.
Adding an adjective like good or bad can make the connotation of democracy clearer.
Another fact that I want to make it clear is that
as the crisis of Western democracy is becoming more serious,
more and more people of insight in the west have noticed the crisis of their own system.
As you may know, Belgium, a small country in Europe,
experienced a political crisis in 2011, lasting for the longest period in its history.
They went through a period of more than 500 days without a central government.
At that time, a fairly large group of intellectuals in Belgium proposed G1000 Manifesto.
You can find it on the Internet.
This Manifesto is very straightforward.
It says that in this world, in addition to democracy,
innovations of anything is happening all over the world.
Companies need innovations.
Scientists must strive to break the barriers of discipline.
Athletes must try to break world records;
Artists must make creative efforts.
But when it comes to politics and the way society is organized,
we are still satisfied with the procedures established in the 1830s.
Why must we hold tight the 200-year-old antiques?
Democracy should be a living organism.
The form of democracy is not fixed.
It should continue to grow in pace with the needs of the times.
Their word made sense.
So many wise philosophers in the west have actually considered democracy very seriously.
No matter what their ideologies are and whether you agree with their views or not,
in general, their consideration is much deeper than those so-called liberals,
who have been spreading western democracy throughout the world.
"All men are created equal", written in "The Declaration of Independence", was adopted in 1776.
In fact, the "men" excluded women, slaves, Chinese, and poor white people.
I always say that the United States didn’t start to implement “one person one vote” until 1965.
The US model and the China model were both newly born.
They can compete against each other.
I have always been more optimistic about the China model.
Certainly, it is still being improved and contains problems.
I dare to say, even with this level,
it is competitive with the US model.
But we still need to reform it to make it better.
At last, I would like to say,
what I said just now is about the views of western thinkers and scholars
on the disadvantages of democracy or how to develop it.
In the future,
I would love to talk about Chinese people’s views on this issue.
That's all for today. Thank you all.
Let’s applaud Prof. Zhang. Please have a seat.
Now it is time for brainstorm.
First, we'd love to hear the view from the pre-production team.
As you mentioned in your speech just now,
democracy can only work under certain conditions.
Many people may ask why China isn't a democracy.
They mean western democracy.
Because Chinese people's political quality isn't high enough.
This is the problem of Taiwan.
Many people in Taiwan believe,
Taiwan is turning democracy into populism because they are low in quality compared to Americans.
But now there are also problems in democracy of the UK and the US.
So do you think that Chinese people has the qualities to practice our democracy?
No. Both content and form of the democracy China is exploring should adjust itself to the national conditions at the current stage.
I also mentioned last time,
why consultative democracy played such an important role?
The first reason is the size of the population.
With such a large population, 10% of disagreement means 140 million people’s opinions.
So we have to consult people's opinions.
In fact this idea began early before.
That’s why direct elections in villages were implemented with "one person one vote".
We even proposed to elect leaders all along in this way,
for the county level, municipal level, provincial level and finally for the state.
After 30 years of practice, frankly speaking, it was not efficient as we had expected.
There’s one thing that I noticed in the speech of Prof. Zhang,
When he talked about the history of western democracy,
he emphasized that we should not oversimplify democracy
and turn it into a procedural system.
It should be well designed and rich in content.
If we focus too much on the democratic form,
it may be a reflection for us rather than misunderstanding.
Everything has two sides like coins.
We only saw the positive side of democracy in the past .
In recent years, the other side is coming into our sight more than before.
For example, democracy may bring about populism or the tyranny of the majority.
What the majority agrees on is not always the right choice.
Two extremist political parties were elected in Italy, Five Star Movement and Lega Nord (Northern League).
Leaders of these two parties both became deputy prime ministers,
while Giuseppe Conte who has little experience and power was proposed as prime minister.
Though the leaders of two parties are appointed by Conte as his deputies, he can't control them.
The deputy prime ministers are very interesting.
They directly paid a visit to the "yellow vests" in France
and supported them to overthrow Macron,
interfering in French internal affairs.
Prof. Zhang mentioned an issue that triggered my thoughts.
That is, whether it's Western democracy or other political institutions,
they all have to be elaborately designed.
This can be manifested not only in a well-designed procedural democracy,
but also in qualified voters and candidates.
A long time ago, western philosophers assumed that
voters were rational and able to consider overall and long-term interests.
But in fact, we find it difficult to achieve.
As an old saying goes,
governing a great country is similar to how you cook a delicate dish.
You must be extremely careful and patient.
Now, it’s time for the audience to raise questions.
OK, that gentleman. He raised his hand first.
Prof. Zhang, I would like to ask a question.
We live in cities.
There are several types of grassroots elections.
One of them of vital importance and close relation with us is the election of the house-owner committee.
Some committees are good, like the one selected in my community,
but I find some committees are not running well in many other communities.
The house-owners are always arguing.
I just want to ask you about this.
Are those committees running as we expected
if we had plans on that issue?
Or what's your comment on it?
Grassroots elections in both villagers' committees of rural areas
and house-owners’ committees in urban areas that you mentioned,
are facing similar challenges.
And we have done some research on the challenges in grassroot elections.
These challenges include the involvement of money, gangsters, and family politics.
Those problems are very common in Chinese culture.
You can cast 20 votes times with 20 ID cards of your family
who have the same surname as you.
You can vote for whoever you like.
They don’t care.
The economic benefits involved in many villages are very large,
about hundreds of millions or even more.
So the competition of elections is very fierce in many places.
Another challenge is rural hollowing.
Many rural residents, especially young people, have moved to the county-level cities or bigger cities.
There’re not enough people to organize a village committee.
This is indeed a new challenge.
One of the measures we are taking
is to re-strengthen the leadership of the party.
Still, we need someone to organize the committees.
Otherwise, problems will arise.
The Communist Party of China makes some arrangements on behalf of the overall interests of the people,
and then we can elect the right people.
Also, as I said, for the existing village committees,
we should strengthen their functions to do a better job.
Appoint some educated cadres to stay in the village to work there for a period of time.
The focus should gradually change from election democracy to governance democracy
so that they can discuss various practical problems.
I think this is more valuable.
It is also the same for the house-owners’ committee,
because it also involves the issue of
how to spend a large sum of money like the maintenance fund of a community.
I myself did some research when I traveled to more than 100 countries,
and I find that various ethnic groups have different strengths and weaknesses.
For example, Britain and the United States are mainly comprised of Anglo-Saxons.
This ethnic group, featuring a relatively strong ability of self-organizing,
love to form a union.
For example, if ten of them meet in a foreign country,
they will set up a club and elect a president.
This fits their culture.
They will make rules by themselves, and everyone follows the rules.
And what is China's comparative advantage?
It has been evolved in our genes for thousands of years.
That is the exam assessment, also called selection now.
This is where China does better.
So I think we are good at taking advantage of our comparative advantages.
We can carry out a variety of experiments and keep doing that.
There must be some pilots that fit their specific conditions in some places.
And those are the results we are looking for.
But basically, I think it's better for China to adopt a combination of selection and election
rather than mere election.
Something happened in the presidential elections in Congo and Nigeria.
One of the cases was that the plane carrying the ballots crashed,
so the two parties decided to re-elect.
Another was that about 48 hours before or even closer to the voting deadline,
the election was postponed,
because the ballot box and the base station weren't ready.
They had no choice but to postpone the election.
As a result, many people traveled hundreds of kilometers to the constituency,
only to be told that it was postponed.
If we only talk about the form,
I think both of these are failed electoral institutions.
Such kind of election failed to meet expectations in terms of efficiency and results.
Are there any questions from the audience behind? Raise your hand please.
This gentleman please.
Hello Prof. Zhang, I have a question for you.
I love reading history books in daily life.
I think China has a long tradition of multi-party systems.
From the Eastern Han Dynasty, relatives in maternal line and eunuchs kept jostling for power.
That was actually the initial stage of the party conflicts.
Later in the Tang Dynasty, the Niu-Faction and Li-Faction contended for power.
Such things happened between the reformative party and conservative party in the Northern Song Dynasty,
and the Donglin Faction and Eunuch Faction in the Ming Dynasty.
Basically, these party conflicts all led to huge losses and perish of the dynasty.
So in our way of developing such a new democratic system suitable for China,
like the one combining selection and election as you mentioned,
how could we avoid the problems that have occurred in our history?
If you really know well about our traditional politics,
in fact, expressions like party conflicts and clique politics convey a derogatory sense.
We actually learned a lesson from that.
Of course, we can define it as a traditional political framework at that time,
instead of the current so-called party conflicts or political party system.
But during the Republican period, we tried American-style democracy indeed,
and more than 300 political parties mushroomed.
You can research into those parties one by one
and you’ll find that none of these parties behaved for the interests of the people.
Also, our tradition does not allow the existence of parties for partial interests
including parties of clique politics.
All my views are based on that China is a civilizational state,
an integration of hundreds of states.
Chinese people have a strong feeling for their own regions.
Leaving aside China, just pay attention to our neighbor, South Korea.
Pay attention to its election.
The presidency is the most dangerous position in Korea.
(laughs) Most of us know this.
Its electoral districts are basically in accordance with "Do",
which equals "province" in China.
People will only vote for candidates from their own province, on most occasions.
Chinese people also share this kind of mindset.
Similarly, people vote for candidates from their province.
It’s a high probability event.
So elections can't be held like that in China.
We have left this way behind.
Of course, we are still exploring
because we still have our own problems.
We keep looking for a solution to improve the way of election.
At least, one consensus that most people have is that
there must be a party for overall interests,
instead of a number of parties for partial interests.
Only in this way can China have a promising future, or we'll fail.
This is a view that some public intellectuals can hardly accept.
When people talk about collectivism,
the spirit of unity to overcome difficulties,
or things like "The Wandering Earth",
they find it hard to accustom themselves to the spirit in them.
But actually, this is China's advantage.
We have a party for overall interest.
That is the Communist Party of China.
They should maintain its advanced nature,
and keep representing the overall interests of Chinese people instead of a minority.
So I say that the biggest difference between Chinese politics and American politics is that
the 100 richest people in our country cannot control the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee,
while the 100 richest people in the United States or even 50 people can control the White House.
Let's keep the questions going. Anyone else?
This lady, please.
Pass her the microphone, please. Thanks.
Hello, Prof. Zhang.
In the process of collecting people's opinions,
I found that the opinions were unfocused.
so I think that democracy is inefficient.
And it is up to the leaders to decide in the end.
Different leading groups have different understandings of democratic centralism and different ways to practice.
In this case, whether democratic centralism can be achieved
may be overly dependent on the quality and ability of the leader.
So what do you think of this issue that democracy is put "on the shelf"?
Thank you.
Different opinions can be discussed and debated.
We are not afraid of competitions at all.
China, be confident.
China now with Zhang Weiwei.
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie
公众号/微博：鹊桥小队翻译组
At the micro-level, I agree with you.
Conditions vary greatly in different places.
Democratic centralism is implemented differently.
It varies greatly in different organizations.
One of the solutions in our country is that
The Organization Department of the Central Committee of the CPC
would assign different cadres to different organizations.
Universities, state-owned enterprises, and private enterprises should have different calibers of personnel.
It's not easy, though, we are trying our best.
Another solution is to rely on inspections.
Two problems are found very common in this process.
One is that some officials are imperious and despotic.
The head decides everything, making the system undemocratic.
And the other is that they are lazy and unwilling to work.
These two issues should be paid attention to during the inspection.
If your leader is lazy or arbitrary,
you can directly call the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection on their cellphones. (laughs）
At the macro level, we have done a good job overall.
The five-year plan is a typical case.
Although we encountered more setbacks in the first 30 years,
I would attribute the rise of China in the past 70 years or the latest 40 years
to the successful implementation of five-year plans,
especially in the latest 40 years.
I agree that in the China model, the role of the top leader is very important,
so we have repeatedly stressed that governing the country depends on talents.
In fact, this is a universal truth.
A company's success is the same.
There would not be Alibaba without Ma Yun.
This is especially true in the China model,
which can be proven in the 40 years of reform and opening up.
Different views can be discussed and debated.
China is the largest tourist exporting country.
Why do they still go back to a country
that you called a country without human rights?
The US publishes a report on the observation on worldwide human rights every year.
What do you think of that?
What should be Chinese Feminism like in your opinion?
When you want to talk about human rights, human rights in China or any other countries,
you should ask the people in that country first.
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie
公众号/微博：鹊桥小队翻译组